Guide to the Marvin Chodorow Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Original Accession, Accession ARCH-2005-180
  - Fellowships Scholarships etc.1958 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Method of Providing Attenuation in Traveling Wave Tubes, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Super Power Talk, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - AGET (Advisory Group on Electron Tubes) Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence 1952 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence 1951 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - European Trip, June-Sept. 1960 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Memos 1958 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - TAC (Technical Advisory Committee) 1957 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence 1954 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence 1953 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Proposal for Creation of a Biophysics Laboratory, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Chodorow- Biophysics Laboratory, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - High Energy Physics Laboratory, misc. correspondence, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Cerenkov and Undulator Radiation (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence 1959 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Memos 1957 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Dr. Chodorow Correspondence 1956 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Chodorow Correspondence from France Sept. 1955-June 1956 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1955 -19 5 7 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Progress Report No.2 (January-June 1947) Microwave Lab, Parts I-III (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Progress Report No.2 (January-June 1947) Microwave Lab, Part IV (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 6th Annual Electron Devices Meeting October 27, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - On Maximum Gain Bandwidth Product in Amplifiers, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Table of Contents, Theory of Bunching (1943) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "Elements of Reflex Klystron Theory" and "Klystron Voltage Amplifiers" (1943) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Theory of Resonator Beam Interaction (1944) (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Small Signal Theory of Longitudinal and Transverse Debunc?ing" (1944), "Small Signal Theory for Multiple Resonator Klystron Amplifier" (1943), and "Klystron Power Amplifier Design" (1942) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Physics 209 Final Exam and Answer Key 1947 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Physics 221, Autumn 1947: Electromagnetic Field I, Syllabus, Problems, Notes (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Microwave Electronics, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Notes for Physics 221 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - E. L. Ginzton European Trip Reports, 1957-1958 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Technical Advisory Meeting, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Technical Advisory Committee Meeting 1959 August (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Technical Advisory Committee Meeting 1959 March (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Technical Advisory Committee Meeting 1958 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Notes (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Stagger Tuned Amplifiers 1944 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Experimental Determination of Impedance Functions by the Use of an Electrolytic Tank, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - On Stagger-Tuned Low-Pass Amplifiers, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Theoretical Limit to Receiver Sensitivity at uhf, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Preliminary Report on Tooth Loaded Waveguide Structure (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Large Signal Behavior of Crossed-Field Traveling Wave Devices, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Review of the Stanford Proposal for a Two-Mile Linear Electron Accelerator 1958 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - MIT Graduation Exercises 1939 and Notes (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - "Aperture Lens Formula Corrected for Space Charge in Stream" (1954) and "Rippled Wall and Rippled Stream Amplifiers" (1954) (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Noise at the Potential Minimum in the High-Frequency Diode (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Fundamental Limitations and Optimum Conditions in Reflex Klystron Oscillators, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Reentrant Resonator Design Charts (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - l0th Annual Conference on Electron Tubes, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Bunching Theory for Two Resonator Klystron Multipliers, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - "Nuclear Induction" (1951) and "Electromagnetic Waves in Iris-Loaded Waveguides" (1947) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Limiting Perveance of Thin Hollow Beams and Beams with Planar Symmetry (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Phase Velocity vs. ka for Slotted Ring Structure (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "The Scattering of Fast Electrons by Atomic Nuclei" (1929) and "On the Zitterbewegung of the Dirac Electron" (1952) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - A New Set of Bessel Functions 1955 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Prelim. Report on Backward Wave Interaction 1952 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Physics 212 Final and Problems 1952 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Coupled Helices for Use in Traveling-Wave Tubes (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Notes 1944 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - An Elementary Introduction to the Theory of the Saddlepoint Method of Integration, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Matrix Treatment of Nuclear Induction (1954) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Linear Electron Accelerator with a Dielectric Loaded Waveguide, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Effect of Varying Disc Thickness in the Radial Direction in a Dielectric Loaded Accelerator, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Effect of Reflections in Linear Accelerators with Feedback ca. 1958 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Block-Nuclear Theory I 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Notebook (p. 1 "Transient behavior of cavity") (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, Intro to Microwaves 1st Quarter 1947 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Varian 25 Years, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Ultrasonic Imaging Systems, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Acoustic Microscope, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence 1974 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Member Data-National Academy of Sciences and American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Experimental Determination of Impedance Functions by the Use of an Electrolytic Tank, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Report on Trip to England and France 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Dr. Chodorow: Travel 1960 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - "The Experimental Use of Coupled Helices for Matching" and Microwave Acoustic and Bulk Device Technique Studies" (1972) (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Remaining Abstracts Not Yet Available 1975 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Washington Trip Dec. 1959 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Conference on Ionization Phenomena in Gases, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - American Physical Society Meetings, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Physics Library (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Search Committee 1981 -1982: Cutler (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Committee 1959-1973 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Stagger Tuned Amplifiers 1944 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Hansen Notes (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Hansen, Transient Response of Wideband Amplifiers, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - American Journal of Physics, May 1983 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Vacuum Tube Research Project (CA Institute of Technology), Quarterly Report No. 11 (1955) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence 1957 (1 of2) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Dr. Chodorow's Correspondence 1957 (2 of2) (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Design and Performance of a High-Power Pulsed Klystron, M.L. Report No. 212, September 1953 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Institute of Electronics Beijing1979-1981 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - SLAC PEP Klystron (slide) 1980 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Talk at RADC 1967 June (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Talk at Ultrasonics Conference 1971 December (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Talk-NSF Grantees Conference, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Talk on Applied Physics at Stanford to Korean Delegation 9/ 10174 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Patent Correspondence and Forms 1976 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Center for History of Physics (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - SPS Space Systems Report to the Committee on Satellite Power Systems (SPS) of the National Academy ofSciences-lune 1981 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - EE Plasma 1961 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Bio Info for Who's Who in Technology Today, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Electron Linear Accelerators for Radiation Therapy, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Articles in French and English (side by side translation) (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Design and Performance of a High Power Pulsed Klystron, Ph.D Dissertation of Ivan Nielsen, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Thesis: Single-Bunch Beam Loading on the SLAC Two-Mile Accelerator 1976 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - ML(Microwave Lab) Memos-General 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Physics Memos 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Physics Memos 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Interoffice Memos- Stanford 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Small box of slides [glass slides possibly from ICMCI conference in Tokyo 1964?]: (Box 19)
    Glass slide: ICEM Magnetron Structure Glass slide: Twystron with RF Driver Circuit Adjusted for Wide; Bandwidth Constant RF Drive Operation; Glass slide: Power Output vs Voltage; Glass slide: Elements of the Re-Entrant Stream Crossed-Field Forward; Wave Amplifier; Glass slide: Distribution of Power in the CW Amplitron; Glass slide: Efficiency Characteristic ofL-Band Pulsed Crossed Field; Amplifier; 3 color slides (travel?); Small envelope labeled T. Tan, contains 2 slides "Acoustic Gaussian Resonator with Gallium-glass lens configuration" and unlabelled; Glass slide labeled 6a-l, photograph of machines
  - ["56 or 58"], 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 19)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2010-128
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2011-534
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2012-076
  - Examination of a General Method of Calculating Energy Bonds of Crystals, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Examination of a General Method of Calculating Energy Bonds of Crystals, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Unlabeled File Pocket, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Solid State Theory Reprints, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Varian Twenty Five Years, 1948-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Quarterly Progress Report No. 14, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Quarterly Progress Report No. 43, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Quarterly Progress Report No. 41, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Electronic Structure of Solids I: the Energy Band Method, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Assorted Physics Papers, circa 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Physics Today, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - I-M, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Copper, 1961-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Envelope containing "The Barbara Kimball Browning Professorship", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Systemizer Table of Contents, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Calculation of Electronic Energy Bands, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Quarterly Progress Report No. 58, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 50-Inch Pocket Slide Rule, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Loose Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Various Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Unlabeled Loose Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Klystron Proposal, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Various Correspondence, 1955-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Small Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Querto, M.C. Shaw, 1969-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Various Reports, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Marvin Chodorow Private and Confidential, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Reprints Karlsruhe, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - A Third Century of Intellectual Leadership, circa 1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Monthly Planner, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Klyston Design Manual, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - RF Properties of Periodic Accelerating Structures for Linear Colliders, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Electromagnetic Waves in Periodic Structures, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Loose Papers, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - SLAC Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Loose Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ivanek Dissertation, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Slides of Graphs, Undated; 6 slide(s) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - SONY, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Unlabeled, 1989; 2 audiocassette(s) (microcasette) (Box 2)
  - D05785 Microcassette Recorder, undated; 1 microcassette-corder (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 75th Birthday, 1978 August (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Color Slides with Images of People, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Klystrons, circa 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Unknown? Subjects, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Club Dinner Recording, 1971 May 27; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Debate on Generalization of Microwave Power, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - T.W.T. Traveling Wave Tubes (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - R.S.R.E. Baldock, 1976 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Path of Electrons Slide, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Picture of Bridge, 1976 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Picture of Mandrel and Disc Assembly, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Unlabeled Images, 1983 Nov (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "2" microcassette, Undated; 1 auidiocassette (microcassette) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Unlabeled Lanier Microcasesette, Undated; 1 audiocassette (microcassette) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 0-228 and 0-99, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - AFOSR Side 1 and 2, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 0-245 and 0-109, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 0-127, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 0-368, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 0-145 and 0-193, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Unlabeled Memorax Audiocassette, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 0-173, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 0-122, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 0-125, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 507454, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)